Guide to the Natalie L. M. Petesch Papers, 1940-2006 SC.2006.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1947-2006; III.
  - Individual Correspondents, 1962-2006; 1.
    - Romero, Armando, 1992-2000 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Sanders, David (Ohio University Press), 2003-2005 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Sarabia, Louis (New Mexico State), 1981 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Schmitt Family, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Schneider, Harold and Mary (Kansas Quarterly), 1978-1979 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Schweitzer, Patricia, 1978-1979 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Serrano, Paco and Marta, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Shea, Suzanne Strempek, 1997-1998 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Shelnutt, Eve (Ohio University), 1990 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Solotaroff, Theodore (Bantam Books), 1978-1980 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - Starkmen, Elaine (Sheer Press), 1980-1981 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Stern, Jerry, 1992-2002 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Sukiennik, Adelaide (Hillman Library), 1994 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - Taylor, Joe, 1985-2002 (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - Villareal, Minerva and Jose, 1987-1992 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Walker, Alice, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Weizenbaum, Nan, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Wendell, Julia (Galileo Press), 1984 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Wentworth, Richard (University of Illinois Press), 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - West, Joan and Dennis, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - West, Paul, 1981-1983 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Wilson, Carlos, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Wright, Nancy (Westminster Writers' Conference), 1989-1990 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Yacovone, Mark (WQED), 1984 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Yamal, Ricardo and Gloria, 1981-1994 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Zimmer, Paul (Iowa Press), 1978-1994 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Zucker, Jack and Helen (The Bridge), 1993-1995 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Corporate Correspondents, 1979-2000; 2.
    - Immigration History Research Center, 1992-1997 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Philadelphia Maritime Museum, 1993 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - University of Idaho, 1980-1982 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Ohio University Press/Swallow Press, 1979-1987 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Ohio University Press, 1995-1999 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - South End Press, 1993 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - WBEZ Stories on Stage, 1999-2000 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Subject-Based and Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1947-2005; 3.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1/2), 1977-1991 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2/2), 1977-1991 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Letters to Various Authors, 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence re: Early Unpublished Novels, 1947-1957 (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Letters from Spain, 1985-1986 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Various Attempts to Publish Short Story Collections, 1970s (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - Letters from Spain and Mexico, 1986-1987 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Various Authors and Editors, 1992-2005 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Letters of Thanks to Writers and Publishers, 1996-1998 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: Translating Immigrant Train Into Polish (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Thank You Notes for Reviewers, 1974-1979 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Agents and Publishers, 1969-1973 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - To Friends and Family from Gainesville, Florida, 1968-1970 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Friends and Family, 1964-1967 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Friends and Relatives, 1959-1967 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Friends and Relatives, 1970-1971 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Publishers (1/3), 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Publishers (2/3), 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Publishers (3/3), 1971-1972 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Friends and Relatives, 1976-1977 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Friends and Relatives, 1971-1973 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Publishers (1/3), 1971-1976 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Publishers (2/3), 1971-1976 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Publishers (3/3), 1971-1976 (Box 44, Folder 6)
- Publicity, Grant and Employment Applications, 1950-1999; IV.
  The material in this series documents many aspects of Petesch's public life as an author. This includes media coverage of her work; documentation from public events and organizations in which she participated; interactions with agents and publishers, including correspondence and promotional materials prepared for her publications; grants and scholarships for which she applied; and honors she received throughout her writing career. Of particular note are the materials relating to the University of Iowa Short Fiction Award she received in 1974 and the numerous press clippings and interviews done for Pittsburgh media outlets, especially WQED public radio. Document types include clippings, correspondence, notes, published promotional material, text of lectures and speeches, and application material for grants and awards.
  The internal arrangement of this series remains largely unchanged from the time of donation. It therefore reflects Petesch's own, somewhat miscellaneous filing system. Confidental letters of recommendation and application materials bearing social security numbers have been removed due to privacy concerns. Audio recordings of readings and appearances by Petesch can be found in Series VII. Multimedia.
  - Letters Written to Promote Kalokovich Novels, 1971-1973 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Lists and Directories of Individuals and Organizations Contacted to Promote The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich, ca. 1972 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Clippings on Alabama, 1963 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Rejection Slips (1/2), 1957-1972 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Rejection Slips (2/2), 1957-1972 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Rejection Letters, Especially for Katinou Kalokovich, 1968-1973 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Xerox of "The Bathouse and Leprosarium" (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographic Sketches for Publishing Occasions, 1977-1990 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Application for Texas Institute of Letters Award, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Long Review of Immigrant Train by Anthony Bukoski in GP Light, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Review of Immigrant Train in The Bridge 7.1, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Reviews of Immigrant Train, 1996-1997 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Reviews of Flowering Mimosa, 1986-1987 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Reviews of Wild With All Regret, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Review of Duncan's Colony and Soul Clap Its Hands and Sing in New Letters 50.1, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Reviews of Flowering Mimosa and Wild With All Regret from In Pittsburgh, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Review of Wild With All Regret in The Balcones Review, Fall 1987 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Reviews of Duncan's Colony, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Statement on the Fiction Awards, Kansas Quarterly, 1981-1982 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Pennsylvania Writers' Catalog, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Advertisements for Readings Available on Cassette (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Lists of Stories for Contest Submission (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Honorific Letters and Clippings, 1973-1991 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Notes Prepared for WQED Interview and Reading of "The Man with the Pinto Bean Hair", 1984 (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Interview in Women and Literature, ca. 1979 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Interview with W.D. Ehrhart (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Interview for Margins, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Advertising Art for The Last Chronicle of Eden, ca. 1981 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Blurbs for The Last Chronicle of Eden/Duncan's Colony (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Reviews of The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich, 1974-1981 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Reviews of After the First Death There Is No Other (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Various Reviews and Interviews (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Review of Katinou Kalokovich in Samisdat 23.4, March 1980 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Interview with Abby Mendelson on Flowering Mimosa, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Talk for Pennsylvania Librarians, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Swedish Translation Request for Duncan's Colony, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Iowa Award Acceptance Speech, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Upon Winning the Iowa Award, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Material Prepared for Radio Interviews, 1979-1984 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Reviews of Soul Clap Its Hands and Sing, ca. 1982 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Outline and Summary of Going Into the War for Scholarship Application, ca. 1980 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Reviews of Duncan's Colony and Wild With All Regret, 1981-1986 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Reviews of Katinou Kalokovich, 1972-1975 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Pennsylvania Writers Collection Catalog, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Pamphlet on WQED "Pennsylvania Fiction Writers" Series, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Notes for WQED Reading and Interview, November 20, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Review of Immigrant Train by Anthony Bukoski in Polish American Studies, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Blurbs and Reviews for Various Publications, ca. 1974-1976 (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Copies of Excerpts from Going Into the War (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - "Waiting" from Going Into the War, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - "The Myth of the Monster Mother-in-Law" from Going Into the War (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Revisions for Going Into the War (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Notes on Iwo Jima for Going Into the War (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Ohio University Press Catalogs Advertising Justina of Andalusia, 1990-1991 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Listing of Justina of Andalusia in the Pennsylvania Center for the Book Catalog, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Flyers and Author's Marketing Questionaire from the University of Iowa for After the First Death There Is No Other, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Book Jacket for Two Novels (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - "Ramon El Conejo" Prepared for University of Iowa Competition, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Illustrations for The Grievance Adjustor (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Catalog Entry Information for the Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Listing of The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich by the Women's Caucus for the Modern Languages, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Interview in Pennsylvania NOW 2.12, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Letter from ANON. re: Printing Excerpt of Katinou Kalokovich, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Announcement of Iowa Award in NOW Oakland News 1.2, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Interview by Patricia Ford in The Pittsburgh Press, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Various Publicity Materials (Ads and Reviews), 1974-1997 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Announcement of Iowa Award in Pennsylvania NOW 2.4, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Advertisement for Katinou Kalokovich in United Sisters Magazine 2.3 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Review of Katinou Kalokovich in Spokeswoman Review 5.7, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Rejection of Katinou Kalokovich from Pyramid Publications, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Clippings re: Iowa Award, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Iowa Award Rejection, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Cover Mock-Up for After the First Death There Is No Other (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Brief Reviews in Jewish Chronicle of Pittsburgh, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Review of Jim Barnes' On Native Ground in Heart Quarterly, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - "A Greeting Card for Immigrants" for New York Times Op-Ed, 1996-1997 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - "Who Am I To Speak?" (Creative Nonfiction Award Winner) with Corrections, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Interview with W.D. Ehrhart in The Greenfield Review 10.1/2, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Reviews of Katinou Kalokovich and After the First Death There Is No Other, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Judging Notes from New Letters Contest, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - National Library Week Readings, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - Material from the Fifth International Conference on the Short Story in English, New Orleans, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 29)
  - Anthony Bukoski's Review of Immigrant Train in Polish American Review, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 30)
  - Paper by Anthony Bukoski on Immigrant Train, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - Radio Play Adaptation of "I, Constanza" (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - Flyers for Justina of Andalusia from Swallow Press, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 33)
  - Material Prepared for Presentation on "The Perfect Short Story," Westminster Writers' Conference, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 34)
  - "The Laughter of Hastings Street" Annotated for Oral Presentation, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 35)
  - "The Man With the Pinto Bean Hair" Annotated for Oral Presentation, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence with Various Agents, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 37)
  - Clipping with Photo re: Iowa Award, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - Copyright for Flowering Mimosa, 1983-1986 (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Copyright for Katinou Kalokovich, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Ohio University Press Contract for Justina of Andalusia, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Possible Awards for Immigrant Train (Box 47, Folder 42)
  - Submission of Immigrant Train for National Book Award, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 43)
  - Ohio University Press Contract for Immigrant Train, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 44)
  - Author's Questionnaire for Ohio University Press re: Immigrant Train (Box 47, Folder 45)
  - Introduction to Reading of "Ellie Blume", 1990 (Box 47, Folder 46)
  - Flyer for Reading at Lion Walk Performing Arts Center (Box 47, Folder 47)
  - Announcement of Reading at Carnegie Library of Squirrel Hill, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 48)
  - Central Pennsylvania Writers' Guild Conference, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 49)
  - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts Writers' Roster Information, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 50)
  - Thank You Letter for Reading at Carnegie Library of Squirrel Hill, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence on Forthcoming Publication of The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Review of The Tupamaros by Major Carlos Wilson, ca. 1980s (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Invitation to Reading Sponsored by New Letters (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Permission to Reprint Stories in Justina of Andalusia (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Rejection Slips for The Eringtons, 1950-1951 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Pitt News Featuring Interview re: After the First Death There Is No Other, February 4, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Copyright Office, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Editorial Changes and Author's Questionaire for Flowering Mimosa, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - "Why I Love Texas" Prepared for Anthology North of the Rio Grande, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Collection of Reviews Prepared for Ohio University Press, 1979-1996 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Biography for Pittsburgh Cultural Trust, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Governor's Award Nomination, 1991-1992 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Statement on "Why I Am a Writer" Prepared for Pittsburgh Cultural Trust, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Notes for WYEP Interview with Roberta Davis, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Guggenheim Grant Application for Soul Clap Its Hands and Sing, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Possible Dedications and Epigraphs for Immigrant Train (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Review of Immigrant Train by Jeff Mock (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Photos, ca. 1974 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Copies of The Pittsburgh New Sun (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Application to Teach at the University for Peace, 1979-1982 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - NEA and Dobie-Paisano Application Materials, 1979-1981 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - NEA Grant Application, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - D.H. Lawrence Fellowship Application, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Application for Fellowship at Paisano, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts Fellowship Application, 1979-1980 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - NEA Grant Application for A Manual for the Corridors, 1992-1993 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - NEA Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - NEA Grant Application, Submitted with "Pillars of Love" and "Cheap Potatoes", 1984 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Dobie-Paisano Fellowship Application, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - NEA Grant Application, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - NEA Grant Rejection, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - NEA Grant Application for the Novel The Last Chronicle of Eden, 1975-1976 (Box 48a, Folder 1)
  - NEA Grant Application for Another Eden, 1991-1992 (Box 48a, Folder 2)
  - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts Grant Application, 1983-1984 (Box 48a, Folder 3)
  - Houghton-Mifflin Literary Fellowship Application, 1975 (Box 48a, Folder 4)
  - NEA Application, 1972-1973 (Box 48a, Folder 5)
  - Report on the Pennsylvania Council on the Arts Grant for Flowering Mimosa, 1984 (Box 48a, Folder 6)
  - Application for Dobie-Paisano Fellowhip and Others, 1975 (Box 48a, Folder 7)
  - School and Employment Application Materials, 1953-1964 (Box 48a, Folder 8)
  - Nominations for Other Writers by Petesch for Awards, 1993-2001 (Box 48a, Folder 8a)
- Education, 1952-1962; V.
  Natalie L.M. Petesch was educated at Detroit public schools. She ran away from home to attend Wayne State University after graduating form high school, but did not complete her bachelor's degree until approxmiately a decade later at Boston University. She went on to earn a master's degree from Brandeis University and a PhD in English literature from the University of Texas at Austin, after which she taught literature at the university level before dedicating herself full-time to her career as an author. This series contains papers, handouts, and lecture notes from Petesch's time as both a student and an instructor at a variety of institutions.
  - Course Notes on American Drama (Box 48a, Folder 9)
  - Course Materials on Chaucer (Box 48a, Folder 10)
  - Note on American History From 1900, ca. 1952-1953 (Box 48a, Folder 11)
  - Notes from Graduate Course on Jonathan Swift (Box 48a, Folder 12)
  - Course Materials on Byron, 1957 (Box 48a, Folder 13)
  - Linguistics Course Notes, University of Texas, 1957-1958 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Various Maps, Brochures, and Clippings for Intended Stories (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Paper on Moliere (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Notes for American Literature Minor Exam, University of Texas (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Teaching Materials on American Literature to 1860, University of Texas (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Notes Prepared for Dissertation Defense, University of Texas, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Maps and Brochures on Detroit (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Maps, Brochures, and Clippings on Boston (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Course Notes on Old English, University of Texas (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Notes for French Exam, University of Texas, 1959 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Course Materials on Elizabethan Drama, Brandeis University (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Notes on World Literature, Southwest Texas State (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Notes and Teaching Materials on American Literature, University of Texas (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Notes for Intended Dissertation on George Meredith (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Linguistics Paper, University of Texas, ca. 1957 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Boston University Diploma, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Materials Required by Boston University for Teaching English in High School (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Offprints and Clippings of Petesch's Writings, 1964-1998; VI.
  Beginning in 1964 and continuing through the 1990s, Petesch regularly published short stories and excerpts from her longer works in newspapers, magazines, and respected literary journals. Though many of these works were eventually culled into collection volumes, the collection of offprints that Petesch maintained documents the evolution of her publishing career and preserves the original publication context for many of her works. Many of her early publications in the 1960s and 1970s were in independent feminist journals. Periodicals in which she was published numerous times include Kansas Quarterly,New Letters, the New Orleans Review, and the University of Windsor Review. This series contains Petesch's personal copies of over sixty periodicals containing her work, arranged chronologically, with duplicates removed.
  - "Li'l Britches" in The Texas Observer (First Published Story), December 11, 1964 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - "The Exile" in New Mexico Quarterly 34.4, Winter 1964-1965 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - "The Truth" in The University Review 31.4, June 1965 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - "Zhenia and the Wicked One" in The New Orleans Review 1.2, Winter 1969 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - "From: The Long Hot Summers of Yasha Kalokovich" in The University of Windsor Review 5.2, Spring 1970 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Excerpt from Yasha K. in Women 1.2, Winter 1970 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "The End of the World" in University of Portland Review 23.1, Spring 1971 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "The Girl Who Was Afraid of Snow" in Moving Out 2.2, February 1972 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - "Tigers" in Moving Out 2.2, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - "Alaric and I" in Libera 2, Summer 1972 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - "The Glassmakers" in Woman Becoming 1.1, December 1972 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - "Freedom" in Women 3.1, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - "Marriage" in Velvet Glove 6, February/March 1972 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Epilogue of Yasha K. in South Dakota Review 10.1, Spring 1972 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Excerpt from Yasha K. in Cloven Hoof 6, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Chapter One of The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich Published in United Sisters Magazine, 1972-1973 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - "The Street" in Michigan Hot Apples 2, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - "The Little Blue Policeman Who Could" in Unfold 2.3, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - "Seeing San Antonio" in Black Maria 2.1/2, Spring/Summer 1973 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - "Thomas" in Quartet 6.42/43, Spring/Summer 1973 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - "The Rock" in Event 3.2, Fall 1973 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - "Jacob K." in The Dekalb Literary Arts Journal 6.3, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - "A Race Riot Recollected in Tranquility" in The New Orleans Review 3.4, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - "A Brief Biography of Ellie Brume" in Kansas Quarterly 6.1, Winter 1973-1974 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - "Ramon El Conejo" in The New Orleans Review 4.3, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - "How I Saved Mickey from the Bomb" in Woman Becoming 2.1, February 1974 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - "My Crystal" in The University of Windsor Review 10.1, Fall/Winter 1974 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - "Losses" in Kansas Quarterly 7.1/2, Winter/Spring 1975 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - "A Golem's Tale" in Anonymous 2, Spring 1975 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - "The Writer's Sense of Place" in South Dakota Review 13.3, Autumn 1975 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - "Picnic Marathons and Non-Proft Insurance for the Aged" in Adena, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Mother Jones 1.1, February/March 1976 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - "Three Poems" by Donald Petesch in Adena 1.2, Fall 1976 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - "Doing It Like Velasquez" in The Remington Review 5, 1977 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - "No Such Thing as Death" in Contempora 2.3, 1977 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - "Socking It Away" in The Louisville Review 2, Spring 1977 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - "Learning to Breathe in the Age of Aquarius" in New Letters 43.4, June 1977 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - "Main Street Morning" in New Letters 44.1, October 1977 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Announcement of Award for "The Bathouse and Leprosarium" in Kansas Quarterly 9.1, Winter 1977 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - "Shopping" in The Louisville Review 4, Spring 1978 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - "Heroes" in New Mexico Humanities Review 1.3, September 1978 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - "The Assassins" in Kansas Quarterly 11.1/2, Winter/Spring 1979 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - "Sunday Evening" in New Mexico Humanities Review 2.1, Spring 1979 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - "Anything New Under the Sun?" in The University of Windsor Review 14.2, Spring/Summer 1979 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - "Be Not Forgetful of Strangers" in New Letters 45.4, June 1979 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - "Life Piled on Life" (interview) in Motheroot Journal 1.1, Winter 1979 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - "The Man With the Pinto Bean Hair" in Slow Loris Reader 4, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 1)